Guide to the University Christian Movement Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Conferences, Series IV
  - Other Conferences, Consultations, and Seminars
    - UCM conferences or related conferences
      - Asian Student and Faculty Conference: Applicants, correspondence, flyers, and planning minutes, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 403)
      - Christian Citizenship Seminar: U.S. Identity in Asia. Conference material of Clark Lobenstine, 1966-1967 (Box 31, Folder 404)
      - Christian Citizenship Seminar: Conference materials, 1967 January 29-February 5 (Box 31, Folder 405)
      - Christian Citizenship Seminar: Government documents including Vietnam in Brief and The Essentials for Peace in Asia, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 406)
      - Christian Citizenship Seminar: List of participants and schedules, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 407)
      - Christian Citizenship Seminar: Planning session meeting minutes and reports, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 408)
      - Christian Citizenship Seminar: Promotional materials, letter to participants, and bibliography, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 409)
      - Christian Citizenship Seminar: Report on participant evaluations, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 410)
      - Christian Citizenship Seminar: Study materials sent to participants, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 411)
      - Consultation: UCM Leadership and Church Boards and Agencies: Correspondence, notes of Paul Schrading, and report, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 412)
      - Southeast Asia International Study Seminar: Brochures, mailing list, schedules, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 413)
      - Southeast Asia International Study Seminar: Correspondence, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 414)
      - Southeast Asia International Study Seminar: Planning Committee meeting minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 32, Folder 415)
      - Southeast Asia International Study Seminar: Memos, reports, research materials, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 416)
      - Southeast Asia International Study Seminar: Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 417)
      - UCM International Development Seminar, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 418)
      - UCM Northeast Regional Conferences: Correspondence and planning reports, 1966-1968 (Box 32, Folder 419)
      - UCM U.S. History Symposium: Correspondence re. program planning and promotional materials, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 420)
      - University and World Change Conference: Correspondence, papers, roster, and schedule, 1966-1967 (Box 32, Folder 421)
      - University and World Change Conference: Correspondence, program planning, meeting minutes, and reports, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 422)
      - University and World Change Conference: Program planning, meeting minutes, and promotional materials, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 423)
      - University and World Change Conference: Correspondence re. program planning, meeting minutes, and reports, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 424)
      - University and World Change Conference: Correspondence, conference materials, University of Kansas newspaper, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 425)
      - University and World Change Conference: Correspondence and reports from discussion groups and workshops, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 426)
      - WSCF Turku '68 Conference: Correspondence re. delegate nominations, 1967-1968 (Box 41, Folder 505)
      - WSCF Turku '68 Conference: Correspondence and report from delegate Howard Spencer, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 506)
      - WSCF Turku '68 Conference: Correspondence, Myona Gul Son, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 507)
      - WSCF Turku '68 Conference: Correspondence, promotional materials, and reports, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 508)
      - WSCF Turku '68 Conference: Preparatory materials, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 509)
      - WSCF Turku '68 Conference: Report "Something was Wrong with Turku '68" by Larry J. Moss, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 510)
    - Other Conferences
      - Church and Society Conference: Correspondence re. student participation, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 427)
      - Church and Society Conference: Correspondence re. UCM attendance, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 428)
      - Church and Society Conference: Conference materials including program, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 429)
      - Church and Society Conference: News clippings and reports, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 430)
      - Church and Society Conference: Planning Committee, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 431)
      - Church and Society Conference: Planning Committee, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 432)
- Organizations, Series V
  - Member Organizations
    - Baptist Student Movement, 1966-1968 (Box 34, Folder 433)
    - Campus Christian Commission of the Standing Conference of Orthodox Bishops. Includes Concern and Newsletter., 1965-1968 (Box 34, Folder 434)
    - Claremont College Church, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 435)
    - Committee for Student Christian Action at Humboldt State College, 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 436)
    - Department of Religious Activities at Gannon College, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 437)
    - Interseminary Movement of Greater Chicago area, 1966-1968 (Box 34, Folder 438)
    - Lutheran Student Association of America. Includes newsletters and pamphlets., 1966-1968 (Box 34, Folder 439)
    - Lutheran Student Association of America. Includes newsletters and pamphlets., 1966-1969 (Box 34, Folder 440)
    - Manchester College, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 441)
    - Methodist Student Movement, Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 442)
    - Methodist Student Movement: Denominational Interpretation, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 443)
    - Methodist Student Movement: Minutes of the National Conference of the Methodist Student Movement, 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 444)
    - Methodist Student Movement: Papers and Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 445)
    - Methodist Student Movement: Publications, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 446)
    - Miscellaneous member programs, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 447)
    - Muhlenberg Christian Association at Muhlenberg College, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 448)
    - National Episcopal Student Committee, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 449)
    - National Federation of Catholic College Students, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 450)
    - National Newman Student Federation: Correspondence and conference materials, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 451)
    - National Newman Student Federation: Correspondence and publications, 1967-1969 (Box 35, Folder 452)
    - National Newman Student Federation: Directory and constitution, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 453)
    - National Newman Student Federation: Newman Apostolate Newsletter, 1966-1968 (Box 36, Folder 454)
    - Newman Congress, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 455)
    - New York State Student Christian Movement, 1965-1966 (Box 36, Folder 456)
    - New York State Student Christian Movement, 1967-1968 (Box 36, Folder 457)
    - Northeast Seminaries Study Conference, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 458)
    - United Campus Christian Fellowship: Guidelines, memos, and newsletters, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 459)
    - UCCF: Publication Campus Resource, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 460)
    - UCCF: Publication Campus Resource, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 461)
    - UCCF: United Campus Christian Fellowship and Westminster Fellowship materials, 1965-1969 (Box 37, Folder 462)
    - UCCF at Michigan State University: Board reports, 1966-1968 (Box 37, Folder 463)
    - UCCF at University of Delaware: Correspondence, publications, and reports, 1967-1968 (Box 37, Folder 464)
    - University Christian Movement at Baker University: By laws and newsletter, 1966-1968 (Box 37, Folder 465)
    - UCM at Colby College: Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 37, Folder 466)
    - UCM at Delhi College: Correspondence, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 467)
    - UCM in New England: Minutes and reports, 1967-1968 (Box 37, Folder 468)
    - UCM at St. Peter's College: Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 37, Folder 469)
    - UCM at Stanford University: Correspondence, field reports, news clippings, 1965-1967 (Box 37, Folder 470)
    - United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.: Directory and newsletter Campus Ministry Memo, 1966-1968 (Box 38, Folder 471)
    - Young Christian Students: YCS Bulletin and miscellaneous materials, 1965-1967 (Box 38, Folder 472)
    - Young Friends of North America: Correspondence and Newsletter: Young Friends of North America, 1962-1967 (Box 38, Folder 473)
    - Young Women's Christian Association: Newsletters and reports, 1966-1968 (Box 38, Folder 474)
  - World Student Christian Federation
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Mission Board Relations, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 475)
    - Asian Study Fellowship meeting minutes, memos, and reports, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 476)
    - Correspondence: Lehtonen, Risto (WSCF Secretary for North America), 1963-1967 (Box 39, Folder 477)
    - Correspondence re. WSCF finances, 1965-1968 (Box 39, Folder 478)
    - Correspondence re. procurement of interpretation equipment for WSCF European Secondary Schools Conference, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 479)
    - Correspondence, Douglas, Bruce (Secretary of WSCF Political Commission), 1966-1968 (Box 39, Folder 480)
    - Correspondence, General, 1966-1968 (Box 39, Folder 481)
    - Correspondence re. WSCF publications, 1966-1968 (Box 39, Folder 482)
    - Correspondence re. Agape Conference "Dissent as a Voice of Hope," Prali, Italy, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 483)
    - Correspondence re. WSCF closing bank account at First National Bank due to bank's business with companies who had ties to Apartheid, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 484)
    - Correspondence re. World Council of Churches Assembly, Uppsala, Sweden, 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 485)
    - Correspondence re. WSCF Frontier Study and Service Project at the United Nations. Includes Lois Simon's article in Motive, 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 486)
    - Correspondence re. printing brochures for WSCF South Africa concerns, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 487)
    - Correspondence re. WSCF General Committee meeting, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 488)
    - Executive Committee memos and reports. Includes notes of Leonard Clough, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 489)
    - General Committee papers and reports, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 490)
    - Minutes of the Ad Hoc WSCF Screening Committee and Officer's Meeting, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 491)
    - North American Committee and proposals for North American Cooperation of WSCF/PAX, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 492)
    - North American Delegation to WSCF Consultation in Prague, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 493)
    - North American Working Party of WSCF Political Commission: China Study Project, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 494)
    - North American Working Party of WSCF Political Commission: China Study Project, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 495)
    - North American Working Party of WSCF Political Commission: China Study Project, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 496)
    - North American Working Party of WSCF Political Commission: China Study Project, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 497)
    - North American Working Party of WSCF Political Commission: China Study Project, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 498)
    - North American Working Party of WSCF Political Commission: China Study Project. Report on Rise of China., 1968 (Box 41, Folder 499)
    - Reports, 1966-1968 (Box 41, Folder 500)
    - WSCF accounts, 1968-1969 (Box 41, Folder 501)
    - WSCF Committee on Foreign Students, 1967-1968 (Box 41, Folder 502)
    - WSCF International Seminar on Middle East: Correspondence with delegates and conference materials, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 503)
    - WSCF International Seminar on Middle East: Correspondence and promotional materials, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 504)
  - Related Organizations
    - National Council of the Churches in Christ in the USA, Department of Higher Education: Committee of National Staff, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 511)
    - NCCC, DHE: Memos and meeting minutes, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 512)
    - NCCC, DHE: Meeting minutes and reports, 1968-1969 (Box 42, Folder 513)
    - NCCC, DHE: Three Year Colloquium on Higher Education program planning, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 514)
    - NCCC, Ecumenical Voluntary Service Committee, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 515)
    - NCCC, Ecumenical Voluntary Service Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 42, Folder 516)
    - Students for a Democratic Society, 1965-1967 (Box 42, Folder 517)
    - Young Men's Christian Association, 1965-1969 (Box 42, Folder 518)
  - Other Organizations
    - Institute of Educational Development, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 519)
    - Pax Romana, 1966-1967 (Box 43, Folder 520)
    - Pax Romana, 1967-1968 (Box 43, Folder 521)
    - War Control Planners, Inc., 1968-1969 (Box 43, Folder 522)
- Collected Material, Series VI
  - William G. Roy Research Files
    - Correspondence re. funding for Roy's study, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 523)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous of Roy's, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 524)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous. Includes Political Committee, Membership, DEG's, and University Inside Out project., 1967-1969 (Box 43, Folder 525)
    - Correspondence with organizers for University Inside Out project, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 526)
    - Correspondence with Organizer for University Inside Out Project, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 527)
    - Committee notes, undated (Box 43, Folder 528)
    - Committee of Returned Peace Corps Volunteers, undated (Box 43, Folder 529)
    - Creation of UCM notes, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 530)
    - Drafts of Roy's research proposal. Includes copy of a letter sent to Charlotte Bunch, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 531)
    - General Committee and Officers Meeting minutes, 1966-1969 (Box 44, Folder 532)
    - Internationalization notes, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 533)
    - Internationalization Task Force, 1968-1969 (Box 44, Folder 534)
    - Membership Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 44, Folder 535)
    - Membership notes, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 536)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 537)
    - Miscellaneous notes and transcriptions, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 538)
    - Miscellaneous UCM letters and reports, 1968-1969 (Box 44, Folder 539)
    - Miscellaneous UCM memos and reports. Includes notes., 1966-1969 (Box 44, Folder 540)
    - Mission propaganda, 1966, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 541)
    - NACLA Newsletter and Pacific Research and World Empire Telegram, 1969-1970 (Box 44, Folder 542)
    - News clippings and releases re. Columbia University termination of University chaplain and Sunday worship, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 543)
    - Notebooks of William G. Roy, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 544)
    - Political Committee. Domestic concerns such as Civil Rights and poverty, 1966-1967 (Box 45, Folder 545)
    - Political Committee. Includes meeting minutes re. Vietnam War and UCM's minimal political stance., 1966-1967 (Box 45, Folder 546)
    - Position papers on UCM direction and strategy, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 547)
    - Radical Caucus notes, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 548)
    - Responses to UCM dissolution, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 549)
    - Second Look newsletter and notes, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 550)
    - Study Resources and Publications Committee, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 551)
    - Theological aspects of UCM notes, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 552)
    - Transcripts of interviews with UCM people, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 553)
    - UCM at Duke University, Emory University, Stanford University, and University of California, Los Angeles, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 554)
    - UCM at the local level notes, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 555)
    - UCM dissolution notes, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 556)
    - "The University Christian Movement: No Fish in the Sea" by William G. Roy, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 557)
    - UCM's relationship and perspective on churches notes, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 558)
    - University Inside Out letters, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 559)
    - Working bibliography, undated (Box 45, Folder 560)
    - World Student Christian Federation, 1966-1968 (Box 45, Folder 561)
  - Paul E. Schrading Papers
    - "Alphabet Soup, the Sixties, and Process '67" paper by Ken Bordner, 1995 (Box 46, Folder 562)
    - Annual Assembly minutes, notes, and reports, 1966-1967 (Box 46, Folder 563)
    - Annual Assembly papers, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 564)
    - Campus ministry articles, 1955, 1960-1966 (Box 46, Folder 565)
    - Campus ministry articles, 1960-1966 (Box 46, Folder 566)
    - Campus ministry articles, 1966-1967 (Box 46, Folder 567)
    - Campus ministry articles, 1968-1969 (Box 47, Folder 568)
    - Education and Social Change: Notes from the UCM Files, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 569)
    - Free Universities: Some Specific Cases, 1967 (Box 47, Folder 570)
    - General Committee and Annual Assembly materials, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 571)
    - General Committee report and news releases re. dissolution of the UCM, 1969 February 27-March 1 (Box 47, Folder 572)
    - Ideology Task Force: Correspondence and reports, 1968-1969 (Box 47, Folder 573)
    - January Study Project report. (Study Project ties into University Inside Out project), 1969 (Box 47, Folder 574)
    - Miscellaneous UCM papers including "The University Christian Movement: a Functional Analysis" by Richard Bowyer and "The University Christian Movement and New forms of Ministry" by Carol Matteson Cox, 1966-1969 (Box 47, Folder 575)
    - motive magazine: Policy statement on the future of motive and Readership Study of, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 576)
    - New England University Christian Movement reports, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 577)
    - The New Left news clippings, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 578)
    - Oberlin College and the [Vietnam] War, 1966-1969 (Box 47, Folder 579)
    - Process '67 material including Notes from the Garage Door journal, 1967-1968 (Box 48, Folder 580)
    - Process '67 and the University Christian Movement: a Report and Interpretation of a Survey of Conference Participants by David S. Wiley and Jackson W. Carroll, 1971 June (Box 48, Folder 581)
    - Radical Education Project materials, 1966 (Box 48, Folder 582)
    - Religion and Higher Education: Articles, pamphlets, and papers, 1959-1966 (Box 48, Folder 583)
    - Students: Articles, news clippings, and papers, 1959-1966 (Box 48, Folder 584)
    - Students: Articles, news clippings, and papers, 1966-1967 (Box 48, Folder 585)
    - Students: Articles news clippings, and papers, 1967-1970 (Box 48, Folder 586)
    - University: Articles, news clippings, and papers, 1966-1969 (Box 48, Folder 587)
    - Typescript of "The University Christian Movement: a Personal Remembrance by Paul E. Schrading. Article published in Journal of Ecumenical Studies, 32 no 3 Summer 1995 (Box 49, Folder 588)
    - Underground newspaper Campus Dialogue, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 589)
    - UCM contacts and mailing lists, 1966-1969 (Box 49, Folder 590)
    - UCM papers and reports. Includes news clippings re. dissolution of UCM., 1966-1969 (Box 49, Folder 591)
    - UCM photographs. Includes two photographs of 1968 protest on Chase and First National City bank., Circa 1966-1969 (Box 49, Folder 592)
    - U.S. History Seminar report, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 593)
    - Writings of Richard Shaull (reprints), 1964-1968 (Box 49, Folder 594)